<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Audiobooks App</string>
    <string name="heaven_of_freedom_string">Heaven of Freedom</string>
    <string name="by_rabindranath_tagore">By Rabindranath Tagore</string>
    <string name="paragraph1">
        Where the mind is without fear and the head is held high. \n
        Where knowledge is free. \n
        Where the world has not been broken up into fragments by narrow domestic walls. \n
        Where words come out from the depth of truth. \n
        Where tireless striving stretches its arms towards perfection. \n
        Where the clear stream of reason has not lost its way into the dreary desert sand of dead habit. \n
        Where the mind is led forward by thee into ever-widening thought and action. \n
        Into that heaven of freedom, my Father, let my country awake.\n\n</string>


    <string name="wandering_singers">Wandering Singers</string>
    <string name="by_sarojini_naidu">By Sarojini Naidu</string>
    <string name="paragraph2">Where the voice of the wind calls our wandering feet, \n
Through echoing forest and echoing street, \n
With lutes in our hands ever-singing we roam, \n
All men are our kindred, the world is our home. \n
Our lays are of cities whose lustre is shed, \n
The laughter and beauty of women long dead; \n
The sword of old battles, the crown of old kings, \n
And happy and simple and sorrowful things. \n
What hope shall we gather, what dreams shall we sow? \n
Where the wind calls our wandering footsteps we go. \n
No love bids us tarry, no joy bids us wait: \n
The voice of the wind is the voice of our fate. \n</string>


    <string name="blue_jay">Blue Jay</string>
    <string name="by_paul_lake">By Paul Lake</string>
    <string name="paragraph3">A sound like a rusty pump beneath our window\n
Woke us at dawn.  Drawing the curtains back,\n
We saw—through milky light, above the doghose—\n
A blue jay lecturing a neighbor\'s cat\n
So fiercely that, at first, it seemed to wonder\n
When birds forgot the diplomacy of flight\n
And met, instead, each charge with a wild swoop,\n
Metallic cry, and angry thrust of beak.\n\n

Later, we found the reason.  Near the fence\n
Among the flowerless stalks of daffodils,\n
A weak piping of feathers.  Too late now to go back\n
To nest again among the sheltering leaves.\n
And so, harrying the dog, routing the cat,\n
And taking sole possession of the yard,\n
The mother swooped all morning.\n

I found her there\n
Still fluttering round my head, still scattering\n
The troops of blackbirds, head cocked toward my car\n
As if it were some lurid animal,\n
When I returned from work.  Still keeping faith.\n
As if what I had found by afternoon\n
Silent and still and hidden in tall grass\n
Might rise again above the fallen world;\n
As if the dead were not past mothering.\n\n</string>


    <string name="a_housewife">A Housewife</string>
    <string name="by_jeff_holt">By Jeff Holt</string>
    <string name="paragraph4">She cleans the tidy house when he\'s not there, \n
Restless as memories best left alone,\n
And tells herself he\'s learning how to care.\n\n

Dusting, she dreams he will caress her hair,\n
His rough hands soft notes on a saxophone.\n
He is so sensitive when he\'s not there.\n\n

Once home, he sprawls out in his leather chair\n
And yells at her to get the telephone.\n
She does, thinking he\'s learning how to care,\n\n

He\'s just a man, and life is never fair.\n
Such phrases, muttered in Mom\'s monotone,\n
Pace through her mind like monks when he is there.\n

That night, beneath him, trembling like a hare,\n
She feels him penetrate her, hears him groan,\n
And tells herself he\'s learning how to care.\n\n

Her life with him is an unquestioned prayer\n
Chanted against an ominous unknown.\n
She cleans the tidy house when he\'s not there\n
And tells herself he\'s learning how to care.\n\n</string>


    <string name="an_immorality">An Immorality</string>
    <string name="by_ezra_pound">By Ezra Pound</string>
    <string name="paragraph5">Sing we for love and idleness,\n
Naught else is worth the having.\n\n

Though I have been in many a land,\n
There is naught else in living.\n\n

And I would rather have my sweet,\n
Though rose-leaves die of grieving,\n\n

Than do high deeds in Hungary\n
To pass all men\'s believing.\n\n</string>


    <string name="silver">Silver</string>
    <string name="by_walter_de_la_mare">By Walter de la Mare</string>
    <string name="paragraph6">Slowly, silently, now the moon \n
Walks the night in her silver shoon; \n
This way, and that, she peers, and sees \n
Silver fruit upon silver trees; \n
One by one the casements catch \n
Her beams beneath the silvery thatch; \n
Couched in his kennel, like a log, \n
With paws of silver sleeps the dog; \n
From their shadowy cote the white breasts peep \n
Of doves in a silver-feathered sleep; \n
A harvest mouse goes scampering by, \n
With silver claws and a silver eye; \n
And moveless fish in the water gleam, \n
By silver reeds in a silver stream. \n\n</string>


    <string name="about_us">About Us</string>
    <string name="paragraphaboutus">Hello enthusiastic book readers, this is your friend Ankit Thapa and I would like to tell you something about my app.\n\n
The AudioBook App is made with the desire to cultivate reading habit amongst the youth by making it easier for them to read or listen more books.
With the advancement in technology and the loss of interest in youths to read books, AudioBook will be a good replacement in the upcoming future as it is a combination of technology and knowledge.
It will help the youth in acquiring knowledge from the  comfort of their home and will be of great help to learn new things in comparatively short period of time.\n\n
       We would be delighted if you have any stories or poems that you would like to share with us.
 Also for my reader friends, if you have any queries, requests for books, feedbacks, or complaints you can contact us through the email or contact us through Whatsapp.\n\n

Email- ankitthapa355@gmail.com \n Contact Us- 7628960040 \n Do contact us if you have ideas related to the app. Till then Happy Reading!\n\


</string>
    <string name="self_made_men">Self-Made Men</string>
    <string name="by_stephen_leacock">By Stephen Leacock</string>
    <string name="tparagraph1"> They were both what we commonly call successful business men--men with well-fed faces, heavy signet rings on fingers like sausages, and broad, comfortable waistcoats, a yard and a half round the equator. They were seated opposite each other at a table of a first-class restaurant, and had fallen into conversation while waiting to give their order to the waiter. Their talk had drifted back to their early days and how each had made his start in life when he first struck New York.\n

\"I tell you what, Jones,\" one of them was saying, \"I shall never forget my first few years in this town. By George, it was pretty uphill work! Do you know, sir, when I first struck this place, I hadn\'t more than fifteen cents to my name, hadn\'t a rag except what I stood up in, and all the place I had to sleep in--you won\'t believe it, but it\'s a gospel fact just the same--was an empty tar barrel. \"No, sir,\" he went on, leaning back and closing up his eyes into an expression of infinite experience, \"no, sir, \" a fellow accustomed to luxury like you has simply no idea what sleeping out in a tar barrel and all that kind of thing is like.\" \n

\"My dear Robinson,\" the other man rejoined briskly, \"if you imagine I\'ve had no experience of hardship of that sort, you never made a bigger mistake in your life. Why, when I first walked into this town I hadn\'t a cent, sir, not a cent, and as for lodging, all the place I had for months and months was an old piano box up a lane, behind a factory. Talk about hardship, I guess I had it pretty rough! You take a fellow that\'s used to a good warm tar barrel and put him into a piano box for a night or two, and you\'ll see mighty soon--\" \n

\"My dear fellow,\" Robinson broke in with some irritation, \"you merely show that you don\'t know what a tar barrel\'s like. Why, on winter nights, when you\'d be shut in there in your piano box just as snug as you please, I used to lie awake shivering, with the draught fairly running in at the bunghole at the back.\" \n

\"Draught!\" sneered the other man, with a provoking laugh, \"draught! Don\'t talk to me about draughts. This box I speak of had a whole darned plank off it, right on the north side too. I used to sit there studying in the evenings, and the snow would blow in a foot deep. And yet, sir,\" he continued more quietly, \"though I know you\'ll not believe it, I don\'t mind admitting that some of the happiest days of my life were spent in that same old box. Ah, those were good old times! Bright, innocent days, I can tell you. I\'d wake up there in the mornings and fairly shout with high spirits. Of course, you may not be able to stand that kind of life--\"  \n\n



\"Not stand it!\" cried Robinson fiercely; \"me not stand it! By gad! I\'m made for it. I just wish I had a taste of the old life again for a while. And as for innocence! Well, I\'ll bet you you weren\'t one-tenth as innocent as I was; no, nor one-fifth, nor one-third! What a grand old life it was! You\'ll swear this is a darned lie and refuse to believe it--but I can remember evenings when I\'d have two or three fellows in, and we\'d sit round and play pedro by a candle half the night.\" \n

\"Two or three!\" laughed Jones; \"why, my dear fellow, I\'ve known half a dozen of us to sit down to supper in my piano box, and have a game of pedro afterwards; yes, and charades and forfeits, and every other darned thing. Mighty good suppers they were too! By Jove, Robinson, you fellows round this town who have ruined your digestions with high living, have no notion of the zest with which a man can sit down to a few potato peelings, or a bit of broken pie crust, or--\" \n

\"Talk about hard food,\" interrupted the other, \"I guess I know all about that. Many\'s the time I\'ve breakfasted off a little cold porridge that somebody was going to throw away from a back-door, or that I\'ve gone round to a livery stable and begged a little bran mash that they intended for the pigs. I\'ll venture to say I\'ve eaten more hog\'s food--\" \n

\"Hog\'s food!\" shouted Robinson, striking his fist savagely on the table, \"I tell you hog\'s food suits me better than--\" \n

He stopped speaking with a sudden grunt of surprise as the waiter appeared with the question: \n

\"What may I bring you for dinner, gentlemen?\" \n

\"Dinner!\" said Jones, after a moment of silence, \"dinner! Oh, anything, nothing--I never care what I eat--give me a little cold porridge, if you\'ve got it, or a chunk of salt pork--anything you like, it\'s all the same to me.\" \n

The waiter turned with an impassive face to Robinson. \n\n



\"You can bring me some of that cold porridge too,\" he said, with a defiant look at Jones; \"yesterday\'s, if you have it, and a few potato peelings and a glass of skim milk.\" \n

There was a pause. Jones sat back in his chair and looked hard across at Robinson. For some moments the two men gazed into each other\'s eyes with a stern, defiant intensity. Then Robinson turned slowly round in his seat and beckoned to the waiter, who was moving off with the muttered order on his lips.\n

\"Here, waiter,\" he said with a savage scowl, \"I guess I\'ll change that order a little. Instead of that cold porridge I\'ll take--um, yes--a little hot partridge. And you might as well bring me an oyster or two on the half shell, and a mouthful of soup (mock-turtle, consomme, anything), and perhaps you might fetch along a dab of fish, and a little peck of Stilton, and a grape, or a walnut.\" \n

The waiter turned to Jones.\n

\"I guess I\'ll take the same,\" he said simply, and added; \"and you might bring a quart of champagne at the same time.\" \n

And nowadays, when Jones and Robinson meet, the memory of the tar barrel and the piano box is buried as far out of sight as a home for the blind under a landslide. \n

They were both what we commonly call successful business men--men with well-fed faces, heavy signet rings on fingers like sausages, and broad, comfortable waistcoats, a yard and a half round the equator. They were seated opposite each other at a table of a first-class restaurant, and had fallen into conversation while waiting to give their order to the waiter. Their talk had drifted back to their early days and how each had made his start in life when he first struck New York. \n

\"I tell you what, Jones,\" one of them was saying, \"I shall never forget my first few years in this town. By George, it was pretty uphill work! Do you know, sir, when I first struck this place, I hadn\'t more than fifteen cents to my name, hadn\'t a rag except what I stood up in, and all the place I had to sleep in--you won\'t believe it, but it\'s a gospel fact just the same--was an empty tar barrel. No, sir,\" he went on, leaning back and closing up his eyes into an expression of infinite experience, \"no, sir, a fellow accustomed to luxury like you has simply no idea what sleeping out in a tar barrel and all that kind of thing is like.\" \n

\"My dear Robinson,\" the other man rejoined briskly, \"if you imagine I\'ve had no experience of hardship of that sort, you never made a bigger mistake in your life. Why, when I first walked into this town I hadn\'t a cent, sir, not a cent, and as for lodging, all the place I had for months and months was an old piano box up a lane, behind a factory. Talk about hardship, I guess I had it pretty rough! You take a fellow that\'s used to a good warm tar barrel and put him into a piano box for a night or two, and you\'ll see mighty soon--\" \n

\"My dear fellow,\" Robinson broke in with some irritation, \"you merely show that you don\'t know what a tar barrel\'s like. Why, on winter nights, when you\'d be shut in there in your piano box just as snug as you please, I used to lie awake shivering, with the draught fairly running in at the bunghole at the back.\" \n

\"Draught!\" sneered the other man, with a provoking laugh, \"draught! Don\'t talk to me about draughts. This box I speak of had a whole darned plank off it, right on the north side too. I used to sit there studying in the evenings, and the snow would blow in a foot deep. And yet, sir,\" he continued more quietly, \"though I know you\'ll not believe it, I don\'t mind admitting that some of the happiest days of my life were spent in that same old box. Ah, those were good old times! Bright, innocent days, I can tell you. I\'d wake up there in the mornings and fairly shout with high spirits. Of course, you may not be able to stand that kind of life--\" \n\n



\"Not stand it!\" cried Robinson fiercely; \"me not stand it! By gad! I\'m made for it. I just wish I had a taste of the old life again for a while. And as for innocence! Well, I\'ll bet you you weren\'t one-tenth as innocent as I was; no, nor one-fifth, nor one-third! What a grand old life it was! You\'ll swear this is a darned lie and refuse to believe it--but I can remember evenings when I\'d have two or three fellows in, and we\'d sit round and play pedro by a candle half the night.\" \n

\"Two or three!\" laughed Jones; \"why, my dear fellow, I\'ve known half a dozen of us to sit down to supper in my piano box, and have a game of pedro afterwards; yes, and charades and forfeits, and every other darned thing. Mighty good suppers they were too! By Jove, Robinson, you fellows round this town who have ruined your digestions with high living, have no notion of the zest with which a man can sit down to a few potato peelings, or a bit of broken pie crust, or--\" \n

\"Talk about hard food,\" interrupted the other, \"I guess I know all about that. Many\'s the time I\'ve breakfasted off a little cold porridge that somebody was going to throw away from a back-door, or that I\'ve gone round to a livery stable and begged a little bran mash that they intended for the pigs. I\'ll venture to say I\'ve eaten more hog\'s food--\" \n

\"Hog\'s food!\" shouted Robinson, striking his fist savagely on the table, \"I tell you hog\'s food suits me better than--\" \n

He stopped speaking with a sudden grunt of surprise as the waiter appeared with the question: \n

\"What may I bring you for dinner, gentlemen?\" \n

\"Dinner!\" said Jones, after a moment of silence, \"dinner! Oh, anything, nothing--I never care what I eat--give me a little cold porridge, if you\'ve got it, or a chunk of salt pork--anything you like, it\'s all the same to me.\" \n

The waiter turned with an impassive face to Robinson. \n

\"You can bring me some of that cold porridge too,\" he said, with a defiant look at Jones; \"yesterday\'s, if you have it, and a few potato peelings and a glass of skim milk.\" \n

There was a pause. Jones sat back in his chair and looked hard across at Robinson. For some moments the two men gazed into each other\'s eyes with a stern, defiant intensity. Then Robinson turned slowly round in his seat and beckoned to the waiter, who was moving off with the muttered order on his lips. \n

\"Here, waiter,\" he said with a savage scowl, \"I guess I\'ll change that order a little. Instead of that cold porridge I\'ll take--um, yes--a little hot partridge. And you might as well bring me an oyster or two on the half shell, and a mouthful of soup (mock-turtle, consomme, anything), and perhaps you might fetch along a dab of fish, and a little peck of Stilton, and a grape, or a walnut.\" \n

The waiter turned to Jones.\n

\"I guess I\'ll take the same,\" he said simply, and added; \"and you might bring a quart of champagne at the same time.\" \n

And nowadays, when Jones and Robinson meet, the memory of the tar barrel and the piano box is buried as far out of sight as a home for the blind under a landslide. \n\n</string>


    <string name="the_lady_or_the_tiger">The Lady, or the Tiger?</string>
    <string name="by_frank_stockton">By Frank Stockton</string>
    <string name="tparagraph2">The Lady, or the Tiger? is one of our Favorite Fairy Tales. It was first published in The Century in 1882, firmly establishing the subtle art of the short story to captivate readers. This story\'s title has become an allegorical expression meaning an unsolvable problem. For teachers and students, enjoy our useful The Lady, or the Tiger? Study Guide.\n
An illustration for the story The Lady, or the Tiger? by the author Frank Stockton\n
In the very olden time, there lived a semi-barbaric king, whose ideas, though somewhat polished and sharpened by the progressiveness of distant Latin neighbors, were still large, florid, and untrammelled, as became the half of him which was barbaric. He was a man of exuberant fancy, and, withal, of an authority so irresistible that, at his will, he turned his varied fancies into facts. He was greatly given to self-communing; and, when he and himself agreed upon any thing, the thing was done. When every member of his domestic and political systems moved smoothly in its appointed course, his nature was bland and genial; but whenever there was a little hitch, and some of his orbs got out of their orbits, he was blander and more genial still, for nothing pleased him so much as to make the crooked straight, and crush down uneven places.\n

Among the borrowed notions by which his barbarism had become semified was that of the public arena, in which, by exhibitions of manly and beastly valor, the minds of his subjects were refined and cultured.\n\n

        But even here the exuberant and barbaric fancy asserted itself. The arena of the king was built, not to give the people an opportunity of hearing the rhapsodies of dying gladiators, nor to enable them to view the inevitable conclusion of a conflict between religious opinions and hungry jaws, but for purposes far better adapted to widen and develop the mental energies of the people. This vast amphitheatre, with its encircling galleries, its mysterious vaults, and its unseen passages, was an agent of poetic justice, in which crime was punished. Or virtue rewarded, by the decrees of an impartial and incorruptible chance.\n

When a subject was accused of a crime of sufficient importance to interest the king, public notice was given that on an appointed day the fate of tile accused person would be decided in the king\'s arena,--a structure which well deserved its name; for, although its form and plan were borrowed -from afar, its purpose emanated solely from the brain of this man, who, every barleycorn a king, knew no tradition to which he owed more allegiance than pleased his fancy, and who ingrafted on every adopted form of human thought and action the rich growth of his barbaric idealism.\n

When all the people had assembled in the galleries, and the king, surrounded by his court, sat high up on his throne of royal state on one side of the arena, he gave a signal, a door beneath him opened, and the accused subject stepped out into the amphitheatre. Directly opposite him, on the other side of the enclosed space, were two doors, exactly alike and side by side. It was the duty and the privilege of the person on trial, to walk directly to these doors and open one of them. He could open either door he pleased: he was subject to no guidance or influence but that of the aforementioned impartial and incorruptible chance. If he opened the one, there came out of it a hungry tiger, the fiercest and most cruel that could be procured, which immediately sprang upon him, and tore him to pieces, as a punishment for his guilt. The moment that the case of the criminal was thus decided, doleful iron bells were clanged, great wails went up from the hired mourners posted on the outer rim of the arena, and the vast audience, with bowed heads and downcast hearts, wended slowly their homeward way, mourning greatly that one so young and fair, or so old and respected, should have merited so dire a fate.\n\n

        But, if the accused person opened the other door, there came forth from it a lady, the most suitable to his years and station that his majesty could select among his fair subjects; and to this lady he was immediately married, as a reward of his innocence. It mattered not that he might already possess a wife and family, or that his affections might be engaged upon an object of his own selection: the king allowed no such subordinate arrangements to interfere with his great scheme of retribution and reward. The exercises, as in the other instance, took place immediately, and in the arena. Another door opened beneath the king, and a priest, followed by a band of choristers\' and dancing maidens blowing joyous airs on golden horns and treading an measure, advanced to where the pair stood side by side; and the wedding was promptly and cheerily solemnized. Then the gay brass bells rang forth their merry peals, the people shouted glad hurrahs, and the innocent man, preceded by children strewing flowers on his path, led his bride to his home.\n

This was the king\'s semi-barbaric method of administering justice. Its perfect fairness is obvious. The criminal could not know out of which door would come the lady: he opened either he pleased, without having the slightest idea whether, in the next instant, he was to be devoured or married. On some occasions the tiger came out of one door, and on some out of the other. The decisions of this tribunal were not only fair, they were positively determinate: the accused person was instantly punished if he found himself guilty; and, if innocent, he was rewarded on the spot, whether he liked it or not. There was no escape from the judgments or the king\'s arena.\n

The institution was a very popular one. When the people gathered together on one of the great trial days, they never knew whether they were to witness a bloody slaughter or a hilarious wedding. This element of uncertainty lent an interest to the occasion which it could not otherwise have attained. Thus, the masses were entertained and pleased, and the thinking part of the community could bring no charge of unfairness against this plan; for did not the accused person have the whole matter in his own hands?\n

This semi-barbaric king had a daughter as blooming as his most florid fancies, and with a soul as fervent and imperious as his own. As is usual in such cases, she was the apple of his eye, and was loved by him above all humanity. Among his courtiers was a young man of that fineness of blood and lowness of station common to the conventional heroes of romance who love royal maidens. This royal maiden was well satisfied with her lover, for he was handsome and brave to a degree unsurpassed in all this kingdom; and she loved him with an ardor that had enough of barbarism in it to make it exceedingly warm and strong. This love affair moved on happily for many months, until one day the king happened to discover its existence. He did not hesitate nor waver in regard to his duty in the premises. The youth was immediately cast into prison, and a day was appointed for his trial in the king\'s arena. This, of course, was an especially important occasion; and his majesty, as well as all the people, was greatly interested in the workings and development of this trial.\n

Never before had such a case occurred; never before had a subject dared to love the daughter of a king. In after-years such things became commonplace enough; but then they were, in no slight degree, novel and startling.\n

The tiger-cages of the kingdom were searched for the most savage and relentless beasts, from which the fiercest monster might be selected for the arena; and the ranks of maiden youth and beauty throughout the land were carefully surveyed by competent judges, in order that he, young man, might have a fitting bride in case fate did not determine for him a different destiny. Of course, everybody knew that the deed with which the accused was charged had been done. He had loved the princess, and neither he, she, nor any one else thought of denying the fact; but the king would not think of allowing any fact of this kind to interfere with the workings of the tribunal, in which he took such great delight and satisfaction. No matter how the affair turned out, the youth would be disposed of; and the king would take an aesthetic pleasure in watching the course of events, which would determine whether or not the young man had done wrong in allowing himself to love the princess.\n\n

        The appointed day arrived. From far and near the people gathered, and thronged the great galleries of the arena; and crowds, unable to gain admittance, massed themselves against its outside walls. The king and his court were in their places, opposite the twin doors,--those fateful portals, so terrible in their similarity.\n

All was ready. The signal was given. A door beneath the royal party opened, and the lover of the princess walked into the arena. Tall, beautiful, fair, his appearance was greeted with a low hum of admiration and anxiety. Half the audience had not known so grand a youth had lived among them. No wonder the princess loved him! What a terrible thing for him to be there!\n

As the youth advanced into the arena, he turned, as the custom was, to bow to the king: but he did not think at all of that royal personage; his eyes were fixed upon the princess, who sat to the right of her father. Had it not been for the moiety of barbarism in her nature, it is probable that lady would not have been there; but her intense and fervid soul would not allow her to be absent on an occasion in which she was so terribly interested. From the moment that the decree had gone forth, that her lover should decide his fate in the king\'s arena, she had thought of nothing, night or day, but this great event and the various subjects connected with it. Possessed of more power, influence, and force of character than any one who had ever before been interested in such a case, she had done what no other person had done,--she had possessed herself of the secret of the doors. She knew in which of the two rooms, that lay behind those doors, stood the cage of the tiger, with its open front, and in which waited the lady. Through these thick doors, heavily curtained with skins on the inside, it was impossible that any noise or suggestion should come from within to the person who should approach to raise the latch of one of them; but gold, and the power of a woman\'s will, had brought the secret to the princess.\n

And not only did she know in which room stood the lady ready to emerge, all blushing and radiant, should her door be opened, but she knew who the lady was. It was one of tile fairest and loveliest of the damsels of the court who had been selected as the reward of the accused youth, should he be proved innocent of the crime of aspiring to one so far above him; and the princess hated her. Often had she seen, or imagined that she had seen, this fair creature throwing glances of admiration upon the person of her lover, and sometimes she thought these glances were perceived and even returned. Now and then she had seen them talking together; it was but for a moment or two, but much can be said in a brief space; it may have been on most unimportant topics, but how could she know that? The girl was lovely, but she had dared to raise her eyes to the loved one of the princess; and, with all the intensity of the savage blood transmitted to her through long lines of wholly barbaric ancestors, she hated the woman who blushed and trembled behind that silent door.\n

When her lover turned and looked at her, and his eye met hers as she sat there paler and whiter than any one in the vast ocean of anxious faces about her, he saw, by that power of quick perception which is given to those whose souls are one, that she knew behind which door crouched the tiger, and behind which stood the lady. He had expected her to know it. He understood her nature, and his soul was assured that she would never rest until she had made plain to herself this thing, hidden to all other lookers-on, even to the king. The only hope for the youth in which there was any element of certainty was based upon the success of the princess in discovering this mystery; and the moment he looked upon her, he saw she had succeeded, as in his soul he knew she would succeed.\n

Then it was that his quick and anxious glance asked the question: \"Which?\" It was as plain to her as if he shouted it from where he stood. There was not an instant to be lost. The question was asked in a Rash; it must be answered in another.\n\n

        Her right arm lay on the cushioned parapet before her. She raised her hand, and made a slight, quick movement toward the right. No one but her lover saw her. Every eye but his was fixed on the man in the arena.\n

He turned, and. with a firm and rapid step he walked across the empty space. Every heart stopped beating, every breath was held, every eye was fixed immovably upon that man. Without the slightest hesitation, he went to the door on the right, and opened it.\n

Now, the point of the story is this: Did the tiger come out of that door, or did the lady?\n

The more we reflect upon this question, the harder it is to answer. It involves a study of the human heart which leads us through devious mazes of passion, out of which it is difficult to find our way. Think of it, fair reader, not as if the decision of the question depended upon yourself, but upon that hot-blooded, semi-barbaric princess, her soul at a white heat beneath the combined fires of despair and jealousy. She had lost him, but who should have him?\n

How often, in her waking hours and in her dreams, had she started in wild horror, and covered her face with her hands, as she thought of her lover opening the door on the other side of which waited the cruel fangs of the tiger!\n

But how much oftener had she seen him at the other door! How in her grievous reveries had she gnashed her teeth, and torn her hair, when she saw his start of rapturous delight as he opened the door of the lady! How her soul had burned in agony when she had seen him rush to meet that woman, with her flushing cheek and sparkling eve of triumph; when she had seen him lead her forth, his whole frame kindled with the joy of recovered life; when she had heard the glad shouts from the multitude, and the wild ringing of the happy bells; when she had seen the priest, with his joyous followers, advance to the couple, and make them man and wife before her very eyes; and when she had seen them walk away together upon their path of flowers, followed by the tremendous shouts of the hilarious multitude, in which her one despairing shriek was lost and drowned!\n

Would it not be better for him to die at once, and go to wait for her in the blessed regions of semi-barbaric futurity?\n

And yet, that awful tiger, those shrieks, that blood!\n

Her decision had been indicated in an instant, but it had been made after days and nights of anguished deliberation. She had known she would be asked, she had decided what she would answer, and, without the slightest hesitation, she had moved her hand to the right.\n\n

The question of her decision is one not to be lightly considered, and it is not for me to presume to set myself up as the one person able to answer it. And so I leave it with all of you: Which came out of the opened door,--the lady, or the tiger?\n\n
</string>


    <string name="the_little_match_girl">The Little Match Girl</string>
    <string name="by_hans_christian_andersen">By Hans Christian Andersen</string>
    <string name="tparagraph3">The Little Match Girl, also titled, The Little Matchstick Girl is one of our Favorite Fairy Tales. Published by Hans Christian Andersen in 1845, it exemplifies his broad literary talent and ability. I personally like to read this story at least twice a year, once in Autumn as the holiday season comes into focus, and then again around the Christmas holiday. It\'s a gentle reminder of the value of compassion and charity. The Little Match Girl Study Guide is a resource for teachers and students.\n
An illustration for the story The Little Match Girl by the author Hans Christian Andersen\n\n
Most terribly cold it was; it snowed, and was nearly quite dark, and evening-- the last evening of the year. In this cold and darkness there went along the street a poor little girl, bareheaded, and with naked feet. When she left home she had slippers on, it is true; but what was the good of that? They were very large slippers, which her mother had hitherto worn; so large were they; and the poor little thing lost them as she scuffled away across the street, because of two carriages that rolled by dreadfully fast.\n

One slipper was nowhere to be found; the other had been laid hold of by an urchin, and off he ran with it; he thought it would do capitally for a cradle when he some day or other should have children himself. So the little maiden walked on with her tiny naked feet, that were quite red and blue from cold. She carried a quantity of matches in an old apron, and she held a bundle of them in her hand. Nobody had bought anything of her the whole livelong day; no one had given her a single farthing.\n

        She crept along trembling with cold and hunger--a very picture of sorrow, the poor little thing!\n

The flakes of snow covered her long fair hair, which fell in beautiful curls around her neck; but of that, of course, she never once now thought. From all the windows the candles were gleaming, and it smelt so deliciously of roast goose, for you know it was New Year\'s Eve; yes, of that she thought.\n

In a corner formed by two houses, of which one advanced more than the other, she seated herself down and cowered together. Her little feet she had drawn close up to her, but she grew colder and colder, and to go home she did not venture, for she had not sold any matches and could not bring a farthing of money: from her father she would certainly get blows, and at home it was cold too, for above her she had only the roof, through which the wind whistled, even though the largest cracks were stopped up with straw and rags.\n

Her little hands were almost numbed with cold. Oh! a match might afford her a world of comfort, if she only dared take a single one out of the bundle, draw it against the wall, and warm her fingers by it. She drew one out. \"Rischt!\" how it blazed, how it burnt! It was a warm, bright flame, like a candle, as she held her hands over it: it was a wonderful light. It seemed really to the little maiden as though she were sitting before a large iron stove, with burnished brass feet and a brass ornament at top. The fire burned with such blessed influence; it warmed so delightfully. The little girl had already stretched out her feet to warm them too; but--the small flame went out, the stove vanished: she had only the remains of the burnt-out match in her hand.\n

She rubbed another against the wall: it burned brightly, and where the light fell on the wall, there the wall became transparent like a veil, so that she could see into the room. On the table was spread a snow-white tablecloth; upon it was a splendid porcelain service, and the roast goose was steaming famously with its stuffing of apple and dried plums. And what was still more capital to behold was, the goose hopped down from the dish, reeled about on the floor with knife and fork in its breast, till it came up to the poor little girl; when--the match went out and nothing but the thick, cold, damp wall was left behind. She lighted another match. Now there she was sitting under the most magnificent Christmas tree: it was still larger, and more decorated than the one which she had seen through the glass door in the rich merchant\'s house.\n\n

        Thousands of lights were burning on the green branches, and gaily-colored pictures, such as she had seen in the shop-windows, looked down upon her. The little maiden stretched out her hands towards them when--the match went out. The lights of the Christmas tree rose higher and higher, she saw them now as stars in heaven; one fell down and formed a long trail of fire.\n

\"Someone is just dead!\" said the little girl; for her old grandmother, the only person who had loved her, and who was now no more, had told her, that when a star falls, a soul ascends to God.\n

She drew another match against the wall: it was again light, and in the lustre there stood the old grandmother, so bright and radiant, so mild, and with such an expression of love.\n

\"Grandmother!\" cried the little one. \"Oh, take me with you! You go away when the match burns out; you vanish like the warm stove, like the delicious roast goose, and like the magnificent Christmas tree!\" And she rubbed the whole bundle of matches quickly against the wall, for she wanted to be quite sure of keeping her grandmother near her. And the matches gave such a brilliant light that it was brighter than at noon-day: never formerly had the grandmother been so beautiful and so tall. She took the little maiden, on her arm, and both flew in brightness and in joy so high, so very high, and then above was neither cold, nor hunger, nor anxiety--they were with God.\n

But in the corner, at the cold hour of dawn, sat the poor girl, with rosy cheeks and with a smiling mouth, leaning against the wall--frozen to death on the last evening of the old year. Stiff and stark sat the child there with her matches, of which one bundle had been burnt. \"She wanted to warm herself,\" people said. No one had the slightest suspicion of what beautiful things she had seen; no one even dreamed of the splendor in which, with her grandmother she had entered on the joys of a new year.\n\n

</string>


    <string name="the_star_lovers">The Star Lovers</string>
    <string name="by_grace_james">By Grace James</string>
    <string name="tparagraph4">The Star Lovers is one of our Favorite Fairy Tales.\n
An illustration for the story The Star Lovers by the author Grace James\n
All you that are true lovers, I beseech you pray the gods for fair weather upon the seventh night of the seventh moon.\n

For patience\’s sake and for dear love\’s sake, pray, and be pitiful that upon that night there may be neither rain, nor hail, nor cloud, nor thunder, nor creeping mist.\n

Hear the sad tale of the Star Lovers and give them your prayers.\n

The Weaving Maiden was the daughter of a Deity of Light. Her dwelling was upon the shore of the Milky Way, which is the Bright River of Heaven. All the day long she sat at her loom and plied her shuttle, weaving the gay garments of the gods. Warp and woof, hour by hour the coloured web grew till it lay fold on fold piled at her feet. Still she never ceased her labour, for she was afraid. She had heard a saying:\n

\“Sorrow, age-long sorrow, shall come upon the Weaving Maiden when she leaves her loom.\” \n

So she laboured, and the gods had garments to spare. But she herself, poor maiden, was ill-clad; she recked nothing of her attire or of the jewels that her father gave her. She went barefoot, and let her hair hang down unconfined. Ever and anon a long lock fell upon the loom, and back she flung it over her shoulder. She did not play with the children of Heaven, or take her pleasure with celestial youths and maidens. She did not love or weep. She was neither glad nor sorry. She sat weaving, weaving ... and wove her being into the many-coloured web.\n\n

        Now her father, the Deity of Light, grew angry. He said, \“Daughter, you weave too much.\” \n

\“It is my duty,\” she said.\n

\“At your age to talk of duty!\” said her father. \“Out upon you!\”\n

\“Wherefore are you displeased with me, my father?\” she said, and her fingers plied the shuttle.\n

\“Are you a stock or a stone, or a pale flower by the wayside?\”\n

\“Nay,\” she said, \“I am none of these.\”\n

\“Then leave your loom, my child, and live; take your pleasure, be as others are.\”\n

\“And wherefore should I be as others are?\” she said.\n

\“Never dare to question me. Come, will you leave your loom?\”\n

She said, \“Sorrow, age-long sorrow, shall come upon the Weaving Maiden when she leaves her loom.\”\n\n

        \“A foolish saying,\” cried her father, \“not worthy of credence. What do we know of age-long sorrow? Are we not gods?\” With that he took her shuttle from her hand gently, and covered the loom with a cloth. And he caused her to be very richly attired, and they put jewels upon her and garlanded her head with flowers of Paradise. And her father gave her for spouse the Herd Boy of Heaven, who tended his flocks upon the banks of the Bright River.\n

Now the Maiden was changed indeed. Her eyes were stars and her lips were ruddy. She went dancing and singing all the day. Long hours she played with the children of Heaven, and she took her pleasure with the celestial youths and maidens. Lightly she went; her feet were shod with silver. Her lover, the Herd Boy, held her by the hand. She laughed so that the very gods laughed with her, and High Heaven re-echoed with sounds of mirth. She was careless; little did she think of duty or of the garments of the gods. As for her loom, she never went near it from one moon\’s end to another.\n

\“I have my life to live,\” she said; \“I\’ll weave it into a web no more.\”\n

And the Herd Boy, her lover, clasped her in his arms. Her face was all tears and smiles, and she hid it on his breast. So she lived her life. But her father, the Deity of Light, was angry.\n

\“It is too much,\” he said. \“Is the girl mad? She will become the laughing-stock of Heaven. Besides, who is to weave the new spring garments of the gods?\”\n

Three times he warned his daughter.\n

Three times she laughed softly and shook her head.\n

\“Your hand opened the door, my father,\” she said, \“but of a surety no hand either of god or of mortal can shut it.\”\n

He said, \“You shall find it otherwise to your cost.\” And he banished the Herd Boy for ever and ever to the farther side of the Bright River. The magpies flew together, from far and near, and they spread their wings for a frail bridge across the river, and the Herd Boy went over by the frail bridge. And immediately the magpies flew away to the ends of the earth and the Weaving Maiden could not follow. She was the saddest thing in Heaven. Long, long she stood upon the shore, and held out her arms to the Herd Boy, who tended his oxen desolate and in tears. Long, long she lay and wept upon the sand. Long, long she brooded, looking on the ground.\n

She arose and went to her loom. She cast aside the cloth that covered it. She took her shuttle in her hand.\n

\“Age-long sorrow,\” she said, \“age-long sorrow!\” Presently she dropped the shuttle. \“Ah,\” she moaned, \“the pain of it,\” and she leaned her head against the loom.\n

But in a little while she said, \“Yet I would not be as once I was. I did not love or weep, I was neither glad nor sorry. Now I love and I weep—I am glad, and I am sorry.\”\n

Her tears fell like rain, but she took up the shuttle and laboured diligently, weaving the garments of the gods. Sometimes the web was grey with grief, sometimes it was rosy with dreams. The gods were fain to go strangely clad. The Maiden\’s father, the Deity of Light, for once was well pleased.\n

\“That is my good, diligent child,\” he said. \“Now you are quiet and happy.\”\n

\“The quiet of dark despair,\” she said. \“Happy! I am the saddest thing in Heaven.\”\n

\“I am sorry,\” said the Deity of Light; \“what shall I do?\”\n

\“Give me back my lover.\”\n

\“Nay, child, that I cannot do. He is banished for ever and ever by the decree of a Deity, that cannot be broken.\”\n

\“I knew it,\” she said.\n

\“Yet something I can do. Listen. On the seventh day of the seventh moon, I will summon the magpies together from the ends of the earth, and they shall be a bridge over the Bright River of Heaven, so that the Weaving Maiden shall lightly cross to the waiting Herd Boy on the farther shore.\”\n

So it was. On the seventh day of the seventh moon came the magpies from far and near. And they spread their wings for a frail bridge. And the Weaving Maiden went over by the frail bridge. Her eyes were like stars, and her heart like a bird in her bosom. And the Herd Boy was there to meet her upon the farther shore.\n

And so it is still, oh, true lovers—upon the seventh day of the seventh moon these two keep their tryst. Only if the rain falls with thunder and cloud and hail, and the Bright River of Heaven is swollen and swift, the magpies cannot make a bridge for the Weaving Maiden. Alack, the dreary time!\n

Therefore, true lovers, pray the gods for fair weather.\n\n
    </string>


    <string name="the_story_of_an_hour">The Story of An Hour</string>
    <string name="by_kate_chopin">By Kate Chopin</string>
    <string name="mparagraph1">This story was first published in 1894 as The Dream of an Hour before being republished under this title in 1895. We encourage students and teachers to use our The Story of An Hour Study Guide and Feminist Literature Study Guide.\n
An illustration for the story The Story of An Hour by the author Kate Chopin.\n
Carl Halsoe, Waiting by the Window, 1863.\n
Knowing that Mrs. Mallard was afflicted with a heart trouble, great care was taken to break to her as gently as possible the news of her husband\'s death.\n

It was her sister Josephine who told her, in broken sentences; veiled hints that revealed in half concealing. Her husband\'s friend Richards was there, too, near her. It was he who had been in the newspaper office when intelligence of the railroad disaster was received, with Brently Mallard\'s name leading the list of \"killed.\" He had only taken the time to assure himself of its truth by a second telegram, and had hastened to forestall any less careful, less tender friend in bearing the sad message.\n\n
        She did not hear the story as many women have heard the same, with a paralyzed inability to accept its significance. She wept at once, with sudden, wild abandonment, in her sister\'s arms. When the storm of grief had spent itself she went away to her room alone. She would have no one follow her.\n

There stood, facing the open window, a comfortable, roomy armchair. Into this she sank, pressed down by a physical exhaustion that haunted her body and seemed to reach into her soul.\n

She could see in the open square before her house the tops of trees that were all aquiver with the new spring life. The delicious breath of rain was in the air. In the street below a peddler was crying his wares. The notes of a distant song which someone was singing reached her faintly, and countless sparrows were twittering in the eaves.\n

There were patches of blue sky showing here and there through the clouds that had met and piled one above the other in the west facing her window.\n

She sat with her head thrown back upon the cushion of the chair, quite motionless, except when a sob came up into her throat and shook her, as a child who has cried itself to sleep continues to sob in its dreams.\n\n
        She was young, with a fair, calm face, whose lines bespoke repression and even a certain strength. But now there was a dull stare in her eyes, whose gaze was fixed away off yonder on one of those patches of blue sky. It was not a glance of reflection, but rather indicated a suspension of intelligent thought.\n

There was something coming to her and she was waiting for it, fearfully. What was it? She did not know; it was too subtle and elusive to name. But she felt it, creeping out of the sky, reaching toward her through the sounds, the scents, the color that filled the air.\n

Now her bosom rose and fell tumultuously. She was beginning to recognize this thing that was approaching to possess her, and she was striving to beat it back with her will--as powerless as her two white slender hands would have been. When she abandoned herself a little whispered word escaped her slightly parted lips. She said it over and over under the breath: \"free, free, free!\" The vacant stare and the look of terror that had followed it went from her eyes. They stayed keen and bright. Her pulses beat fast, and the coursing blood warmed and relaxed every inch of her body.\n

She did not stop to ask if it were or were not a monstrous joy that held her. A clear and exalted perception enabled her to dismiss the suggestion as trivial. She knew that she would weep again when she saw the kind, tender hands folded in death; the face that had never looked save with love upon her, fixed and gray and dead. But she saw beyond that bitter moment a long procession of years to come that would belong to her absolutely. And she opened and spread her arms out to them in welcome.\n

There would be no one to live for during those coming years; she would live for herself. There would be no powerful will bending hers in that blind persistence with which men and women believe they have a right to impose a private will upon a fellow-creature. A kind intention or a cruel intention made the act seem no less a crime as she looked upon it in that brief moment of illumination.\n

And yet she had loved him--sometimes. Often she had not. What did it matter! What could love, the unsolved mystery, count for in the face of this possession of self-assertion which she suddenly recognized as the strongest impulse of her being!\n

\"Free! Body and soul free!\" she kept whispering.\n

Josephine was kneeling before the closed door with her lips to the keyhole, imploring for admission. \"Louise, open the door! I beg; open the door--you will make yourself ill. What are you doing, Louise? For heaven\'s sake open the door.\"\n

\"Go away. I am not making myself ill.\" No; she was drinking in a very elixir of life through that open window.\n

Her fancy was running riot along those days ahead of her. Spring days, and summer days, and all sorts of days that would be her own. She breathed a quick prayer that life might be long. It was only yesterday she had thought with a shudder that life might be long.\n

She arose at length and opened the door to her sister\'s importunities. There was a feverish triumph in her eyes, and she carried herself unwittingly like a goddess of Victory. She clasped her sister\'s waist, and together they descended the stairs. Richards stood waiting for them at the bottom.\n

Someone was opening the front door with a latchkey. It was Brently Mallard who entered, a little travel-stained, composedly carrying his grip-sack and umbrella. He had been far from the scene of the accident, and did not even know there had been one. He stood amazed at Josephine\'s piercing cry; at Richards\' quick motion to screen him from the view of his wife.\n

When the doctors came they said she had died of heart disease--of the joy that kills.\n\n</string>


    <string name="eve_s_diary">Eve\'s Diary</string>
    <string name="by_mark_twain">By Mark Twain</string>
    <string name="mparagraph2">An illustration for the story Eve\'s Diary by the author Mark Twain.\n
SATURDAY.--I am almost a whole day old, now. I arrived yesterday. That is as it seems to me. And it must be so, for if there was a day-before-yesterday I was not there when it happened, or I should remember it. It could be, of course, that it did happen, and that I was not noticing. Very well; I will be very watchful now, and if any day-before-yesterdays happen I will make a note of it. It will be best to start right and not let the record get confused, for some instinct tells me that these details are going to be important to the historian some day. For I feel like an experiment, I feel exactly like an experiment; it would be impossible for a person to feel more like an experiment than I do, and so I am coming to feel convinced that that is what I am--an experiment; just an experiment, and nothing more.\n

Then if I am an experiment, am I the whole of it? No, I think not; I think the rest of it is part of it. I am the main part of it, but I think the rest of it has its share in the matter. Is my position assured, or do I have to watch it and take care of it? The latter, perhaps. Some instinct tells me that eternal vigilance is the price of supremacy. [That is a good phrase, I think, for one so young.]\n\n
        Everything looks better today than it did yesterday. In the rush of finishing up yesterday, the mountains were left in a ragged condition, and some of the plains were so cluttered with rubbish and remnants that the aspects were quite distressing. Noble and beautiful works of art should not be subjected to haste; and this majestic new world is indeed a most noble and beautiful work. And certainly marvelously near to being perfect, notwithstanding the shortness of the time. There are too many stars in some places and not enough in others, but that can be remedied presently, no doubt. The moon got loose last night, and slid down and fell out of the scheme --a very great loss; it breaks my heart to think of it. There isn\'t another thing among the ornaments and decorations that is comparable to it for beauty and finish. It should have been fastened better. If we can only get it back again-- But of course there is no telling where it went to. And besides, whoever gets it will hide it; I know it because I would do it myself. I believe I can be honest in all other matters, but I already begin to realize that the core and center of my nature is love of the beautiful, a passion for the beautiful, and that it would not be safe to trust me with a moon that belonged to another person and that person didn\'t know I had it. I could give up a moon that I found in the daytime, because I should be afraid some one was looking; but if I found it in the dark, I am sure I should find some kind of an excuse for not saying anything about it. For I do love moons, they are so pretty and so romantic. I wish we had five or six; I would never go to bed; I should never get tired lying on the moss-bank and looking up at them.\n

Stars are good, too. I wish I could get some to put in my hair. But I suppose I never can. You would be surprised to find how far off they are, for they do not look it. When they first showed, last night, I tried to knock some down with a pole, but it didn\'t reach, which astonished me; then I tried clouds till I was all tired out, but I never got one. It was because I am left-handed and cannot throw good. Even when I aimed at the one I wasn\'t after I couldn\'t hit the other one, though I did make some close shots, for I saw the black blot of the cloud sail right into the midst of the golden clusters forty or fifty times, just barely missing them, and if I could have held out a little longer maybe I could have got one.\n\n
        So I cried a little, which was natural, I suppose, for one of my age, and after I was rested I got a basket and started for a place on the extreme rim of the circle, where the stars were close to the ground and I could get them with my hands, which would be better, anyway, because I could gather them tenderly then, and not break them. But it was farther than I thought, and at last I had go give it up; I was so tired I couldn\'t drag my feet another step; and besides, they were sore and hurt me very much.\n

I couldn\'t get back home; it was too far and turning cold; but I found some tigers and nestled in among them and was most adorably comfortable, and their breath was sweet and pleasant, because they live on strawberries. I had never seen a tiger before, but I knew them in a minute by the stripes. If I could have one of those skins, it would make a lovely gown.\n

Today I am getting better ideas about distances. I was so eager to get hold of every pretty thing that I giddily grabbed for it, sometimes when it was too far off, and sometimes when it was but six inches away but seemed a foot--alas, with thorns between! I learned a lesson; also I made an axiom, all out of my own head --my very first one; THE SCRATCHED EXPERIMENT SHUNS THE THORN. I think it is a very good one for one so young.\n

I followed the other Experiment around, yesterday afternoon, at a distance, to see what it might be for, if I could. But I was not able to make out. I think it is a man. I had never seen a man, but it looked like one, and I feel sure that that is what it is. I realize that I feel more curiosity about it than about any of the other reptiles. If it is a reptile, and I suppose it is; for it has frowzy hair and blue eyes, and looks like a reptile. It has no hips; it tapers like a carrot; when it stands, it spreads itself apart like a derrick; so I think it is a reptile, though it may be architecture.\n

I was afraid of it at first, and started to run every time it turned around, for I thought it was going to chase me; but by and by I found it was only trying to get away, so after that I was not timid any more, but tracked it along, several hours, about twenty yards behind, which made it nervous and unhappy. At last it was a good deal worried, and climbed a tree. I waited a good while, then gave it up and went home.\n

Today the same thing over. I\'ve got it up the tree again.\n\n

SUNDAY.--It is up there yet. Resting, apparently. But that is a subterfuge: Sunday isn\'t the day of rest; Saturday is appointed for that. It looks to me like a creature that is more interested in resting than it anything else. It would tire me to rest so much. It tires me just to sit around and watch the tree. I do wonder what it is for; I never see it do anything.\n

They returned the moon last night, and I was so happy! I think it is very honest of them. It slid down and fell off again, but I was not distressed; there is no need to worry when one has that kind of neighbors; they will fetch it back. I wish I could do something to show my appreciation. I would like to send them some stars, for we have more than we can use. I mean I, not we, for I can see that the reptile cares nothing for such things.\n

It has low tastes, and is not kind. When I went there yesterday evening in the gloaming it had crept down and was trying to catch the little speckled fishes that play in the pool, and I had to clod it to make it go up the tree again and let them alone. I wonder if that is what it is for? Hasn\'t it any heart? Hasn\'t it any compassion for those little creature? Can it be that it was designed and manufactured for such ungentle work? It has the look of it. One of the clods took it back of the ear, and it used language. It gave me a thrill, for it was the first time I had ever heard speech, except my own. I did not understand the words, but they seemed expressive.\n\n
        When I found it could talk I felt a new interest in it, for I love to talk; I talk, all day, and in my sleep, too, and I am very interesting, but if I had another to talk to I could be twice as interesting, and would never stop, if desired.\n

If this reptile is a man, it isn\'t an it, is it? That wouldn\'t be grammatical, would it? I think it would be he. I think so. In that case one would parse it thus: nominative, HE; dative, HIM; possessive, HIS\'N. Well, I will consider it a man and call it he until it turns out to be something else. This will be handier than having so many uncertainties.\n\n

NEXT WEEK SUNDAY.--All the week I tagged around after him and tried to get acquainted. I had to do the talking, because he was shy, but I didn\'t mind it. He seemed pleased to have me around, and I used the sociable \"we\" a good deal, because it seemed to flatter him to be included.\n\n

WEDNESDAY.--We are getting along very well indeed, now, and getting better and better acquainted. He does not try to avoid me any more, which is a good sign, and shows that he likes to have me with him. That pleases me, and I study to be useful to him in every way I can, so as to increase his regard. During the last day or two I have taken all the work of naming things off his hands, and this has been a great relief to him, for he has no gift in that line, and is evidently very grateful. He can\'t think of a rational name to save him, but I do not let him see that I am aware of his defect. Whenever a new creature comes along I name it before he has time to expose himself by an awkward silence. In this way I have saved him many embarrassments. I have no defect like this. The minute I set eyes on an animal I know what it is. I don\'t have to reflect a moment; the right name comes out instantly, just as if it were an inspiration, as no doubt it is, for I am sure it wasn\'t in me half a minute before. I seem to know just by the shape of the creature and the way it acts what animal it is.\n

When the dodo came along he thought it was a wildcat--I saw it in his eye. But I saved him. And I was careful not to do it in a way that could hurt his pride. I just spoke up in a quite natural way of pleasing surprise, and not as if I was dreaming of conveying information, and said, \"Well, I do declare, if there isn\'t the dodo!\" I explained--without seeming to be explaining --how I know it for a dodo, and although I thought maybe he was a little piqued that I knew the creature when he didn\'t, it was quite evident that he admired me. That was very agreeable, and I thought of it more than once with gratification before I slept. How little a thing can make us happy when we feel that we have earned it!\n\n

THURSDAY.--my first sorrow. Yesterday he avoided me and seemed to wish I would not talk to him. I could not believe it, and thought there was some mistake, for I loved to be with him, and loved to hear him talk, and so how could it be that he could feel unkind toward me when I had not done anything? But at last it seemed true, so I went away and sat lonely in the place where I first saw him the morning that we were made and I did not know what he was and was indifferent about him; but now it was a mournful place, and every little thing spoke of him, and my heart was very sore. I did not know why very clearly, for it was a new feeling; I had not experienced it before, and it was all a mystery, and I could not make it out.\n

But when night came I could not bear the lonesomeness, and went to the new shelter which he has built, to ask him what I had done that was wrong and how I could mend it and get back his kindness again; but he put me out in the rain, and it was my first sorrow.\n\n

SUNDAY.--It is pleasant again, now, and I am happy; but those were heavy days; I do not think of them when I can help it.\n

        I tried to get him some of those apples, but I cannot learn to throw straight. I failed, but I think the good intention pleased him. They are forbidden, and he says I shall come to harm; but so I come to harm through pleasing him, why shall I care for that harm?\n\n

MONDAY.--This morning I told him my name, hoping it would interest him. But he did not care for it. It is strange. If he should tell me his name, I would care. I think it would be pleasanter in my ears than any other sound.\n

He talks very little. Perhaps it is because he is not bright, and is sensitive about it and wishes to conceal it. It is such a pity that he should feel so, for brightness is nothing; it is in the heart that the values lie. I wish I could make him understand that a loving good heart is riches, and riches enough, and that without it intellect is poverty.\n

Although he talks so little, he has quite a considerable vocabulary. This morning he used a surprisingly good word. He evidently recognized, himself, that it was a good one, for he worked in in twice afterward, casually. It was good casual art, still it showed that he possesses a certain quality of perception. Without a doubt that seed can be made to grow, if cultivated.\n

Where did he get that word? I do not think I have ever used it.\n

No, he took no interest in my name. I tried to hide my disappointment, but I suppose I did not succeed. I went away and sat on the moss-bank with my feet in the water. It is where I go when I hunger for companionship, some one to look at, some one to talk to. It is not enough--that lovely white body painted there in the pool --but it is something, and something is better than utter loneliness. It talks when I talk; it is sad when I am sad; it comforts me with its sympathy; it says, \"Do not be downhearted, you poor friendless girl; I will be your friend.\" It IS a good friend to me, and my only one; it is my sister.\n

That first time that she forsook me! ah, I shall never forget that --never, never. My heart was lead in my body! I said, \"She was all I had, and now she is gone!\" In my despair I said, \"Break, my heart; I cannot bear my life any more!\" and hid my face in my hands, and there was no solace for me. And when I took them away, after a little, there she was again, white and shining and beautiful, and I sprang into her arms!\n

That was perfect happiness; I had known happiness before, but it was not like this, which was ecstasy. I never doubted her afterward. Sometimes she stayed away--maybe an hour, maybe almost the whole day, but I waited and did not doubt; I said, \"She is busy, or she is gone on a journey, but she will come.\" And it was so: she always did. At night she would not come if it was dark, for she was a timid little thing; but if there was a moon she would come. I am not afraid of the dark, but she is younger than I am; she was born after I was. Many and many are the visits I have paid her; she is my comfort and my refuge when my life is hard--and it is mainly that.\n\n

TUESDAY.--All the morning I was at work improving the estate; and I purposely kept away from him in the hope that he would get lonely and come. But he did not.\n

At noon I stopped for the day and took my recreation by flitting all about with the bees and the butterflies and reveling in the flowers, those beautiful creatures that catch the smile of God out of the sky and preserve it! I gathered them, and made them into wreaths and garlands and clothed myself in them while I ate my luncheon --apples, of course; then I sat in the shade and wished and waited. But he did not come.\n

But no matter. Nothing would have come of it, for he does not care for flowers. He called them rubbish, and cannot tell one from another, and thinks it is superior to feel like that. He does not care for me, he does not care for flowers, he does not care for the painted sky at eventide--is there anything he does care for, except building shacks to coop himself up in from the good clean rain, and thumping the melons, and sampling the grapes, and fingering the fruit on the trees, to see how those properties are coming along?\n

I laid a dry stick on the ground and tried to bore a hole in it with another one, in order to carry out a scheme that I had, and soon I got an awful fright. A thin, transparent bluish film rose out of the hole, and I dropped everything and ran! I thought it was a spirit, and I WAS so frightened! But I looked back, and it was not coming; so I leaned against a rock and rested and panted, and let my limps go on trembling until they got steady again; then I crept warily back, alert, watching, and ready to fly if there was occasion; and when I was come near, I parted the branches of a rose-bush and peeped through--wishing the man was about, I was looking so cunning and pretty--but the sprite was gone. I went there, and there was a pinch of delicate pink dust in the hole. I put my finger in, to feel it, and said OUCH! and took it out again. It was a cruel pain. I put my finger in my mouth; and by standing first on one foot and then the other, and grunting, I presently eased my misery; then I was full of interest, and began to examine.\n

I was curious to know what the pink dust was. Suddenly the name of it occurred to me, though I had never heard of it before. It was FIRE! I was as certain of it as a person could be of anything in the world. So without hesitation I named it that--fire.\n

I had created something that didn\'t exist before; I had added a new thing to the world\'s uncountable properties; I realized this, and was proud of my achievement, and was going to run and find him and tell him about it, thinking to raise myself in his esteem --but I reflected, and did not do it. No--he would not care for it. He would ask what it was good for, and what could I answer? for if it was not GOOD for something, but only beautiful, merely beautiful-- So I sighed, and did not go. For it wasn\'t good for anything; it could not build a shack, it could not improve melons, it could not hurry a fruit crop; it was useless, it was a foolishness and a vanity; he would despise it and say cutting words. But to me it was not despicable; I said, \"Oh, you fire, I love you, you dainty pink creature, for you are BEAUTIFUL--and that is enough!\" and was going to gather it to my breast. But refrained. Then I made another maxim out of my head, though it was so nearly like the first one that I was afraid it was only a plagiarism: \"THE BURNT EXPERIMENT SHUNS THE FIRE.\"\n\n

        I wrought again; and when I had made a good deal of fire-dust I emptied it into a handful of dry brown grass, intending to carry it home and keep it always and play with it; but the wind struck it and it sprayed up and spat out at me fiercely, and I dropped it and ran. When I looked back the blue spirit was towering up and stretching and rolling away like a cloud, and instantly I thought of the name of it--SMOKE!--though, upon my word, I had never heard of smoke before.\n

Soon brilliant yellow and red flares shot up through the smoke, and I named them in an instant--FLAMES--and I was right, too, though these were the very first flames that had ever been in the world. They climbed the trees, then flashed splendidly in and out of the vast and increasing volume of tumbling smoke, and I had to clap my hands and laugh and dance in my rapture, it was so new and strange and so wonderful and so beautiful!\n

He came running, and stopped and gazed, and said not a word for many minutes. Then he asked what it was. Ah, it was too bad that he should ask such a direct question. I had to answer it, of course, and I did. I said it was fire. If it annoyed him that I should know and he must ask; that was not my fault; I had no desire to annoy him. After a pause he asked:\n\n

\"How did it come?\"\n

Another direct question, and it also had to have a direct answer.\n

\"I made it.\"\n

The fire was traveling farther and farther off. He went to the edge of the burned place and stood looking down, and said:\n

\"What are these?\"\n

\"Fire-coals.\"\n

He picked up one to examine it, but changed his mind and put it down again. Then he went away. NOTHING interests him.\n

But I was interested. There were ashes, gray and soft and delicate and pretty--I knew what they were at once. And the embers; I knew the embers, too. I found my apples, and raked them out, and was glad; for I am very young and my appetite is active. But I was disappointed; they were all burst open and spoiled. Spoiled apparently; but it was not so; they were better than raw ones. Fire is beautiful; some day it will be useful, I think.\n\n

FRIDAY.--I saw him again, for a moment, last Monday at nightfall, but only for a moment. I was hoping he would praise me for trying to improve the estate, for I had meant well and had worked hard. But he was not pleased, and turned away and left me. He was also displeased on another account: I tried once more to persuade him to stop going over the Falls. That was because the fire had revealed to me a new passion--quite new, and distinctly different from love, grief, and those others which I had already discovered--FEAR. And it is horrible!--I wish I had never discovered it; it gives me dark moments, it spoils my happiness, it makes me shiver and tremble and shudder. But I could not persuade him, for he has not discovered fear yet, and so he could not understand me.\n

Extract from Adam\'s Diary\n

Perhaps I ought to remember that she is very young, a mere girl and make allowances. She is all interest, eagerness, vivacity, the world is to her a charm, a wonder, a mystery, a joy; she can\'t speak for delight when she finds a new flower, she must pet it and caress it and smell it and talk to it, and pour out endearing names upon it. And she is color-mad: brown rocks, yellow sand, gray moss, green foliage, blue sky; the pearl of the dawn, the purple shadows on the mountains, the golden islands floating in crimson seas at sunset, the pallid moon sailing through the shredded cloud-rack, the star-jewels glittering in the wastes of space--none of them is of any practical value, so far as I can see, but because they have color and majesty, that is enough for her, and she loses her mind over them. If she could quiet down and keep still a couple minutes at a time, it would be a reposeful spectacle. In that case I think I could enjoy looking at her; indeed I am sure I could, for I am coming to realize that she is a quite remarkably comely creature --lithe, slender, trim, rounded, shapely, nimble, graceful; and once when she was standing marble-white and sun-drenched on a boulder, with her young head tilted back and her hand shading her eyes, watching the flight of a bird in the sky, I recognized that she was beautiful.\n\n

MONDAY NOON.--If there is anything on the planet that she is not interested in it is not in my list. There are animals that I am indifferent to, but it is not so with her. She has no discrimination, she takes to all of them, she thinks they are all treasures, every new one is welcome.\n

When the mighty brontosaurus came striding into camp, she regarded it as an acquisition, I considered it a calamity; that is a good sample of the lack of harmony that prevails in our views of things. She wanted to domesticate it, I wanted to make it a present of the homestead and move out. She believed it could be tamed by kind treatment and would be a good pet; I said a pet twenty-one feet high and eighty-four feet long would be no proper thing to have about the place, because, even with the best intentions and without meaning any harm, it could sit down on the house and mash it, for any one could see by the look of its eye that it was absent-minded.\n

Still, her heart was set upon having that monster, and she couldn\'t give it up. She thought we could start a dairy with it, and wanted me to help milk it; but I wouldn\'t; it was too risky. The sex wasn\'t right, and we hadn\'t any ladder anyway. Then she wanted to ride it, and look at the scenery. Thirty or forty feet of its tail was lying on the ground, like a fallen tree, and she thought she could climb it, but she was mistaken; when she got to the steep place it was too slick and down she came, and would have hurt herself but for me.\n
        Was she satisfied now? No. Nothing ever satisfies her but demonstration; untested theories are not in her line, and she won\'t have them. It is the right spirit, I concede it; it attracts me; I feel the influence of it; if I were with her more I think I should take it up myself. Well, she had one theory remaining about this colossus: she thought that if we could tame it and make him friendly we could stand in the river and use him for a bridge. It turned out that he was already plenty tame enough--at least as far as she was concerned --so she tried her theory, but it failed: every time she got him properly placed in the river and went ashore to cross over him, he came out and followed her around like a pet mountain. Like the other animals. They all do that.\n\n

FRIDAY.--Tuesday--Wednesday--Thursday--and today: all without seeing him. It is a long time to be alone; still, it is better to be alone than unwelcome.\n

I HAD to have company--I was made for it, I think--so I made friends with the animals. They are just charming, and they have the kindest disposition and the politest ways; they never look sour, they never let you feel that you are intruding, they smile at you and wag their tail, if they\'ve got one, and they are always ready for a romp or an excursion or anything you want to propose. I think they are perfect gentlemen. All these days we have had such good times, and it hasn\'t been lonesome for me, ever. Lonesome! No, I should say not. Why, there\'s always a swarm of them around --sometimes as much as four or five acres--you can\'t count them; and when you stand on a rock in the midst and look out over the furry expanse it is so mottled and splashed and gay with color and frisking sheen and sun-flash, and so rippled with stripes, that you might think it was a lake, only you know it isn\'t; and there\'s storms of sociable birds, and hurricanes of whirring wings; and when the sun strikes all that feathery commotion, you have a blazing up of all the colors you can think of, enough to put your eyes out.\n

We have made long excursions, and I have seen a great deal of the world; almost all of it, I think; and so I am the first traveler, and the only one. When we are on the march, it is an imposing sight --there\'s nothing like it anywhere. For comfort I ride a tiger or a leopard, because it is soft and has a round back that fits me, and because they are such pretty animals; but for long distance or for scenery I ride the elephant. He hoists me up with his trunk, but I can get off myself; when we are ready to camp, he sits and I slide down the back way.\n

The birds and animals are all friendly to each other, and there are no disputes about anything. They all talk, and they all talk to me, but it must be a foreign language, for I cannot make out a word they say; yet they often understand me when I talk back, particularly the dog and the elephant. It makes me ashamed. It shows that they are brighter than I am, for I want to be the principal Experiment myself--and I intend to be, too.\n

I have learned a number of things, and am educated, now, but I wasn\'t at first. I was ignorant at first. At first it used to vex me because, with all my watching, I was never smart enough to be around when the water was running uphill; but now I do not mind it. I have experimented and experimented until now I know it never does run uphill, except in the dark. I know it does in the dark, because the pool never goes dry, which it would, of course, if the water didn\'t come back in the night. It is best to prove things by actual experiment; then you KNOW; whereas if you depend on guessing and supposing and conjecturing, you never get educated.\n

Some things you CAN\'T find out; but you will never know you can\'t by guessing and supposing: no, you have to be patient and go on experimenting until you find out that you can\'t find out. And it is delightful to have it that way, it makes the world so interesting. If there wasn\'t anything to find out, it would be dull. Even trying to find out and not finding out is just as interesting as trying to find out and finding out, and I don\'t know but more so. The secret of the water was a treasure until I GOT it; then the excitement all went away, and I recognized a sense of loss.\n

By experiment I know that wood swims, and dry leaves, and feathers, and plenty of other things; therefore by all that cumulative evidence you know that a rock will swim; but you have to put up with simply knowing it, for there isn\'t any way to prove it--up to now. But I shall find a way--then THAT excitement will go. Such things make me sad; because by and by when I have found out everything there won\'t be any more excitements, and I do love excitements so! The other night I couldn\'t sleep for thinking about it.\n

At first I couldn\'t make out what I was made for, but now I think it was to search out the secrets of this wonderful world and be happy and thank the Giver of it all for devising it. I think there are many things to learn yet--I hope so; and by economizing and not hurrying too fast I think they will last weeks and weeks. I hope so. When you cast up a feather it sails away on the air and goes out of sight; then you throw up a clod and it doesn\'t. It comes down, every time. I have tried it and tried it, and it is always so. I wonder why it is? Of course it DOESN\'T come down, but why should it SEEM to? I suppose it is an optical illusion. I mean, one of them is. I don\'t know which one. It may be the feather, it may be the clod; I can\'t prove which it is, I can only demonstrate that one or the other is a fake, and let a person take his choice.\n

By watching, I know that the stars are not going to last. I have seen some of the best ones melt and run down the sky. Since one can melt, they can all melt; since they can all melt, they can all melt the same night. That sorrow will come--I know it. I mean to sit up every night and look at them as long as I can keep awake; and I will impress those sparkling fields on my memory, so that by and by when they are taken away I can by my fancy restore those lovely myriads to the black sky and make them sparkle again, and double them by the blur of my tears.\n

After the Fall\n

When I look back, the Garden is a dream to me. It was beautiful, surpassingly beautiful, enchantingly beautiful; and now it is lost, and I shall not see it any more.\n

The Garden is lost, but I have found HIM, and am content. He loves me as well as he can; I love him with all the strength of my passionate nature, and this, I think, is proper to my youth and sex. If I ask myself why I love him, I find I do not know, and do not really much care to know; so I suppose that this kind of love is not a product of reasoning and statistics, like one\'s love for other reptiles and animals. I think that this must be so. I love certain birds because of their song; but I do not love Adam on account of his singing--no, it is not that; the more he sings the more I do not get reconciled to it. Yet I ask him to sing, because I wish to learn to like everything he is interested in. I am sure I can learn, because at first I could not stand it, but now I can. It sours the milk, but it doesn\'t matter; I can get used to that kind of milk.\n\n

</string>


    <string name="the_grasshopper_and_the_ant">The Grasshopper and the Ant</string>
    <string name="by_aesop">By Aesop</string>
    <string name="mparagraph3">
The Grasshopper and the Ant (or Ants) is more commonly referred to by its better known title, The Ant and the Grasshopper. This fable\'s moral lesson emphasizes the twin values of hard and planning for the future. It is one of Favorite Fairy Tales.\n
An illustration for the story The Grasshopper and the Ant by the author Aesop.\n
One bright day in late autumn a family of Ants were bustling about in the warm sunshine, drying out the grain they had stored up during the summer, when a starving Grasshopper, his fiddle under his arm, came up and humbly begged for a bite to eat.\n\n

\"What!\" cried the Ants in surprise, \"haven\'t you stored anything away for the winter? What in the world were you doing all last summer?\"\n

\"I didn\'t have time to store up any food,\" whined the Grasshopper; \"I was so busy making music that before I knew it the summer was gone.\"\n

The Ants shrugged their shoulders in disgust.\n

\"Making music, were you?\" they cried. \"Very well; now dance!\" And they turned their backs on the Grasshopper and went on with their work.\n

There\'s a time for work and a time for play.\n\n</string>


    <string name="the_necklace">The Necklace</string>
    <string name="by_guy_de_maupassant">By Guy de Maupassant</string>
    <string name="mparagraph4">The Necklace (1884) is a famous short story and morality tale that is widely read in classrooms throughout the world.\n
Get more out of the story with our The Necklace Study Guide.\n
An illustration for the story The Necklace by the author Guy de Maupassant.\n\n
The girl was one of those pretty and charming young creatures who sometimes are born, as if by a slip of fate, into a family of clerks. She had no dowry, no expectations, no way of being known, understood, loved, married by any rich and distinguished man; so she let herself be married to a little clerk of the Ministry of Public Instruction.\n

She dressed plainly because she could not dress well, but she was unhappy as if she had really fallen from a higher station; since with women there is neither caste nor rank, for beauty, grace and charm take the place of family and birth. Natural ingenuity, instinct for what is elegant, a supple mind are their sole hierarchy, and often make of women of the people the equals of the very greatest ladies.\n

        Mathilde suffered ceaselessly, feeling herself born to enjoy all delicacies and all luxuries. She was distressed at the poverty of her dwelling, at the bareness of the walls, at the shabby chairs, the ugliness of the curtains. All those things, of which another woman of her rank would never even have been conscious, tortured her and made her angry. The sight of the little Breton peasant who did her humble housework aroused in her despairing regrets and bewildering dreams. She thought of silent antechambers hung with Oriental tapestry, illumined by tall bronze candelabra, and of two great footmen in knee breeches who sleep in the big armchairs, made drowsy by the oppressive heat of the stove. She thought of long reception halls hung with ancient silk, of the dainty cabinets containing priceless curiosities and of the little coquettish perfumed reception rooms made for chatting at five o\'clock with intimate friends, with men famous and sought after, whom all women envy and whose attention they all desire.\n

When she sat down to dinner, before the round table covered with a tablecloth in use three days, opposite her husband, who uncovered the soup tureen and declared with a delighted air, \"Ah, the good soup! I don\'t know anything better than that,\" she thought of dainty dinners, of shining silverware, of tapestry that peopled the walls with ancient personages and with strange birds flying in the midst of a fairy forest; and she thought of delicious dishes served on marvellous plates and of the whispered gallantries to which you listen with a sphinxlike smile while you are eating the pink meat of a trout or the wings of a quail.\n

She had no gowns, no jewels, nothing. And she loved nothing but that. She felt made for that. She would have liked so much to please, to be envied, to be charming, to be sought after.\n

She had a friend, a former schoolmate at the convent, who was rich, and whom she did not like to go to see any more because she felt so sad when she came home.\n\n

        But one evening her husband reached home with a triumphant air and holding a large envelope in his hand.\n

\"There,\" said he, \"there is something for you.\"\n

She tore the paper quickly and drew out a printed card which bore these words:\n

        The Minister of Public Instruction and Madame Georges Ramponneau request the honor of M. and Madame Loisel\'s company at the palace of the Ministry on Monday evening, January 18th.\n

        Instead of being delighted, as her husband had hoped, she threw the invitation on the table crossly, muttering:\n

\"What do you wish me to do with that?\"\n

\"Why, my dear, I thought you would be glad. You never go out, and this is such a fine opportunity. I had great trouble to get it. Every one wants to go; it is very select, and they are not giving many invitations to clerks. The whole official world will be there.\"\n

She looked at him with an irritated glance and said impatiently:\n

\"And what do you wish me to put on my back?\"\n

He had not thought of that. He stammered:\n

\"Why, the gown you go to the theatre in. It looks very well to me.\"\n

He stopped, distracted, seeing that his wife was weeping. Two great tears ran slowly from the corners of her eyes toward the corners of her mouth.\n

\"What\'s the matter? What\'s the matter?\" he answered.\n

By a violent effort she conquered her grief and replied in a calm voice, while she wiped her wet cheeks:\n

\"Nothing. Only I have no gown, and, therefore, I can\'t go to this ball. Give your card to some colleague whose wife is better equipped than I am.\"\n

He was in despair. He resumed:\n

\"Come, let us see, Mathilde. How much would it cost, a suitable gown, which you could use on other occasions--something very simple?\"\n

She reflected several seconds, making her calculations and wondering also what sum she could ask without drawing on herself an immediate refusal and a frightened exclamation from the economical clerk.\n

Finally she replied hesitating:\n

\"I don\'t know exactly, but I think I could manage it with four hundred francs.\"\n

He grew a little pale, because he was laying aside just that amount to buy a gun and treat himself to a little shooting next summer on the plain of Nanterre, with several friends who went to shoot larks there of a Sunday.\n

But he said:\n

\"Very well. I will give you four hundred francs. And try to have a pretty gown.\"\n

The day of the ball drew near and Madame Loisel seemed sad, uneasy, anxious. Her frock was ready, however. Her husband said to her one evening:\n\n

        The Necklace, Napoleon\'s collection. "\What is the matter? Come, you have seemed very queer these last three days.\"\n

And she answered:\n

\"It annoys me not to have a single piece of jewelry, not a single ornament, nothing to put on. I shall look poverty-stricken. I would almost rather not go at all.\"\n

\"You might wear natural flowers,\" said her husband. \"They\'re very stylish at this time of year. For ten francs you can get two or three magnificent roses.\"\n

She was not convinced.\n

\"No; there\'s nothing more humiliating than to look poor among other women who are rich.\"\n

\"How stupid you are!\" her husband cried. \"Go look up your friend, Madame Forestier, and ask her to lend you some jewels. You\'re intimate enough with her to do that.\"\n

She uttered a cry of joy:\n

\"True! I never thought of it.\"\n

The next day she went to her friend and told her of her distress.\n

Madame Forestier went to a wardrobe with a mirror, took out a large jewel box, brought it back, opened it and said to Madame Loisel:\n

\"Choose, my dear.\"\n

She saw first some bracelets, then a pearl necklace, then a Venetian gold cross set with precious stones, of admirable workmanship. She tried on the ornaments before the mirror, hesitated and could not make up her mind to part with them, to give them back. She kept asking:\n

\"Haven\'t you any more?\"\n

\"Why, yes. Look further; I don\'t know what you like.\"\n

Suddenly she discovered, in a black satin box, a superb diamond necklace, and her heart throbbed with an immoderate desire. Her hands trembled as she took it. She fastened it round her throat, outside her high-necked waist, and was lost in ecstasy at her reflection in the mirror.\n

Then she asked, hesitating, filled with anxious doubt:\n

\"Will you lend me this, only this?\"\n

\"Why, yes, certainly.\"\n

She threw her arms round her friend\'s neck, kissed her passionately, then fled with her treasure.\n

The night of the ball arrived. Madame Loisel was a great success. She was prettier than any other woman present, elegant, graceful, smiling and wild with joy. All the men looked at her, asked her name, sought to be introduced. All the attaches of the Cabinet wished to waltz with her. She was remarked by the minister himself.\n\n

        She danced with rapture, with passion, intoxicated by pleasure, forgetting all in the triumph of her beauty, in the glory of her success, in a sort of cloud of happiness comprised of all this homage, admiration, these awakened desires and of that sense of triumph which is so sweet to woman\'s heart.\n

She left the ball about four o\'clock in the morning. Her husband had been sleeping since midnight in a little deserted anteroom with three other gentlemen whose wives were enjoying the ball.\n

He threw over her shoulders the wraps he had brought, the modest wraps of common life, the poverty of which contrasted with the elegance of the ball dress. She felt this and wished to escape so as not to be remarked by the other women, who were enveloping themselves in costly furs.\n

Loisel held her back, saying: \"Wait a bit. You will catch cold outside. I will call a cab.\"\n

But she did not listen to him and rapidly descended the stairs. When they reached the street they could not find a carriage and began to look for one, shouting after the cabmen passing at a distance.\n

They went toward the Seine in despair, shivering with cold. At last they found on the quay one of those ancient night cabs which, as though they were ashamed to show their shabbiness during the day, are never seen round Paris until after dark.\n

It took them to their dwelling in the Rue des Martyrs, and sadly they mounted the stairs to their flat. All was ended for her. As to him, he reflected that he must be at the ministry at ten o\'clock that morning.\n

She removed her wraps before the glass so as to see herself once more in all her glory. But suddenly she uttered a cry. She no longer had the necklace around her neck!\n

\"What is the matter with you?\" demanded her husband, already half undressed.\n

She turned distractedly toward him.\n

\"I have--I have--I\'ve lost Madame Forestier\'s necklace,\" she cried.\n

He stood up, bewildered.\n

\"What!--how? Impossible!\"\n

They looked among the folds of her skirt, of her cloak, in her pockets, everywhere, but did not find it.\n

\"You\'re sure you had it on when you left the ball?\" he asked.\n

\"Yes, I felt it in the vestibule of the minister\'s house.\"\n

\"But if you had lost it in the street we should have heard it fall. It must be in the cab.\"\n

\"Yes, probably. Did you take his number?\"\n

\"No. And you--didn\'t you notice it?\"\n

\"No.\"\n

They looked, thunderstruck, at each other. At last Loisel put on his clothes.\n

\"I shall go back on foot,\" said he, \"over the whole route, to see whether I can find it.\"\n

He went out. She sat waiting on a chair in her ball dress, without strength to go to bed, overwhelmed, without any fire, without a thought.\n

Her husband returned about seven o\'clock. He had found nothing.\n

He went to police headquarters, to the newspaper offices to offer a reward; he went to the cab companies--everywhere, in fact, whither he was urged by the least spark of hope.\n

She waited all day, in the same condition of mad fear before this terrible calamity.\n

Loisel returned at night with a hollow, pale face. He had discovered nothing.\n

\"You must write to your friend,\" said he, \"that you have broken the clasp of her necklace and that you are having it mended. That will give us time to turn round.\"\n

She wrote at his dictation.\n

At the end of a week they had lost all hope. Loisel, who had aged five years, declared:\n

\"We must consider how to replace that ornament.\"\n

The next day they took the box that had contained it and went to the jeweler whose name was found within. He consulted his books.\n

\"It was not I, madame, who sold that necklace; I must simply have furnished the case.\"\n\n

        Then they went from jeweler to jeweler, searching for a necklace like the other, trying to recall it, both sick with chagrin and grief.\n

They found, in a shop at the Palais Royal, a string of diamonds that seemed to them exactly like the one they had lost. It was worth forty thousand francs. They could have it for thirty-six.\n

So they begged the jeweler not to sell it for three days yet. And they made a bargain that he should buy it back for thirty-four thousand francs, in case they should find the lost necklace before the end of February.\n

Loisel possessed eighteen thousand francs which his father had left him. He would borrow the rest.\n

He did borrow, asking a thousand francs of one, five hundred of another, five louis here, three louis there. He gave notes, took up ruinous obligations, dealt with usurers and all the race of lenders. He compromised all the rest of his life, risked signing a note without even knowing whether he could meet it; and, frightened by the trouble yet to come, by the black misery that was about to fall upon him, by the prospect of all the physical privations and moral tortures that he was to suffer, he went to get the new necklace, laying upon the jeweler\'s counter thirty-six thousand francs.\n

When Madame Loisel took back the necklace Madame Forestier said to her with a chilly manner:\n

\"You should have returned it sooner; I might have needed it.\"\n

She did not open the case, as her friend had so much feared. If she had detected the substitution, what would she have thought, what would she have said? Would she not have taken Madame Loisel for a thief?\n

Thereafter Madame Loisel knew the horrible existence of the needy. She bore her part, however, with sudden heroism. That dreadful debt must be paid. She would pay it. They dismissed their servant; they changed their lodgings; they rented a garret under the roof.\n

She came to know what heavy housework meant and the odious cares of the kitchen. She washed the dishes, using her dainty fingers and rosy nails on greasy pots and pans. She washed the soiled linen, the shirts and the dishcloths, which she dried upon a line; she carried the slops down to the street every morning and carried up the water, stopping for breath at every landing. And dressed like a woman of the people, she went to the fruiterer, the grocer, the butcher, a basket on her arm, bargaining, meeting with impertinence, defending her miserable money, sou by sou.\n

Every month they had to meet some notes, renew others, obtain more time.\n

Her husband worked evenings, making up a tradesman\'s accounts, and late at night he often copied manuscript for five sous a page.\n

This life lasted ten years.\n

At the end of ten years they had paid everything, everything, with the rates of usury and the accumulations of the compound interest.\n

Madame Loisel looked old now. She had become the woman of impoverished households--strong and hard and rough. With frowsy hair, skirts askew and red hands, she talked loud while washing the floor with great swishes of water. But sometimes, when her husband was at the office, she sat down near the window and she thought of that gay evening of long ago, of that ball where she had been so beautiful and so admired.\n

What would have happened if she had not lost that necklace? Who knows? who knows? How strange and changeful is life! How small a thing is needed to make or ruin us!\n

But one Sunday, having gone to take a walk in the Champs Elysees to refresh herself after the labors of the week, she suddenly perceived a woman who was leading a child. It was Madame Forestier, still young, still beautiful, still charming.\n

Madame Loisel felt moved. Should she speak to her? Yes, certainly. And now that she had paid, she would tell her all about it. Why not?\n

She went up.\n

\"Good-day, Jeanne.\"\n

The other, astonished to be familiarly addressed by this plain good-wife, did not recognize her at all and stammered:\n

\"But--madame!--I do not know---- You must have mistaken.\"\n

\"No. I am Mathilde Loisel.\"\n

Her friend uttered a cry.\n

\"Oh, my poor Mathilde! How you are changed!\"\n
\"Yes, I have had a pretty hard life, since I last saw you, and great poverty--and that because of you!\"\n

\"Of me! How so?\"\n

\"Do you remember that diamond necklace you lent me to wear at the ministerial ball?\"\n

\"Yes. Well?\"\n

\"Well, I lost it.\"\n

\"What do you mean? You brought it back.\"\n

\"I brought you back another exactly like it. And it has taken us ten years to pay for it. You can understand that it was not easy for us, for us who had nothing. At last it is ended, and I am very glad.\"\n

Madame Forestier had stopped.\n

\"You say that you bought a necklace of diamonds to replace mine?\"\n

\"Yes. You never noticed it, then! They were very similar.\"\n

And she smiled with a joy that was at once proud and ingenuous.\n

Madame Forestier, deeply moved, took her hands.\n

\"Oh, my poor Mathilde! Why, my necklace was paste! It was worth at most only five hundred francs!\"\n\n

</string>
    <string name="the_game_part_1">The Game Part 1</string>
    <string name="by_mary_roberts_rinehart">By Mary Roberts Rinehart</string>
    <string name="paragraph01">
The Game is Rinehart\'s thoroughly engaging story about a \"fatherless wharf-rat and childless engineer; the man acting on the dour Scot principle of chastening whomsoever he loveth, and the boy cherishing a hate that was really only hurt love.\"\n
An illustration for the story The Game by the author Mary Roberts Rinehart\n
Steamship RMS Lusitania, Popular Science, 1918\n

        I The Red Un was very red; even his freckles were red rather than copper-coloured. And he was more prodigal than most kings, for he had two crowns on his head. Also his hair grew in varying directions, like a wheatfields after a storm. He wore a coat without a tail, but with brass buttons to compensate, and a celluloid collar with a front attached. It was the Red Un\'s habit to dress first and wash after, as saving labour; instead of his neck he washed his collar.\n

The Red Un was the Chief Engineer\'s boy and rather more impressive than the Chief, who was apt to decry his own greatness. It was the Red Un\'s duty to look after the Chief, carry in his meals, make his bed, run errands, and remind him to get his hair cut now and then. It was the Red Un\'s pleasure to assist unassumingly in the surveillance of that part of the ship where the great god, Steam, ruled an underworld of trimmers and oilers and stokers and assistant engineers--and even, with reservations, the Chief. The Red Un kept a sharp eye on the runs and read the Chief\'s log daily--so much coal in the bunkers; so much water in the wells; so many engine-room miles in twenty-four hours--which, of course, are not sea miles exactly, there being currents and winds, and God knows what, to waste steam on.\n

The Red Un, like the assistants, was becoming a bear on the speed market. He had learned that, just when the engines get heated enough to work like demons, and there is a chance to break a record and get a letter from the management, some current or other will show up--or a fog, which takes the very tripe out of the cylinders and sends the bridge yapping for caution.\n



The Red Un was thirteen; and he made the Chief\'s bed by pulling the counterpane neatly and smoothly over the chaos underneath--and got away with it, the Chief being weary at night. Also, in odd moments he made life miserable for the crew. Up to shortly before, he had had to use much energy and all his wits to keep life in his starved little body; and even keeping an eye on the log and the Chief\'s hair, and slipping down into the engine room, where he had no manner of business, hardly used up his activities. However, he did not lie and he looked the Chief square in the eye, as man to man.\n

The Chief had salvaged him out of the Hudson, when what he had taken for a bobbing red tomato had suddenly revealed a blue face and two set and desperate eyes. After that the big Scot had forgotten all about him, except the next day when he put on his shoes, which had shrunk in the drying. The liner finished coaling about that time, took on passengers, luggage, steamer baskets and a pilot, and, having stowed the first two, examined the cards on the third and dropped the last, was pointed, nose to the east wind, for the race.\n

The arrow on the twin dials pointed to Stand By! for the long voyage--three thousand miles or so without a stop. The gong, and then Half Ahead!--great elbows thrust up and down, up and down; the grunt of power overcoming inertia, followed by the easy swing of limitless strength. Full Ahead!--and so off again for the great struggle--man\'s wits and the engines and the mercy of God against the upreaching of the sea.\n

The Chief, who sometimes dreamed his greatness, but who ignored it waking, snapped his watch shut.\n

\"Eleven-eleven!\" he said to the Senior Second. \"Well, here\'s luck!\" That is what he said aloud; to himself he always said a bit of a prayer, realising perhaps even more than the bridge how little man\'s wits count in the great equation. He generally said something to the effect that \"After all, it\'s up to Thee, O Lord!\"\n



He shook hands with the Senior Second, which also was his habit; and he smiled too, but rather grimly. They were playing a bit of a game, you see; and so far the Chief had won all the tricks--just an amusing little game and nothing whatever to do with a woman; the Second was married, but the Chief had put all such things out of his head years before, when he was a youngster and sailing to the Plate. Out of his head, quite certainly; but who dreams of greatness for himself alone? So the Chief, having glanced about and run his hand caressingly over various fearful and pounding steel creatures, had climbed up the blistering metal staircase to his room at the top and was proceeding to put down eleven-eleven and various other things that the first cabin never even heard of, when he felt that he was being stared at from behind.\n

Now and then, after shore leave, a drunken trimmer or stoker gets up to the Chief\'s room and has to be subdued by the power of executive eye or the strength of executive arm. As most Chiefs are Scots, the eye is generally sufficient. So the Chief, mightily ferocious, turned about, eye set, as one may say, to annihilate a six-foot trimmer in filthy overalls and a hangover, and saw--a small red-haired boy in a Turkish towel.\n

The boy quailed rather at the eye, but he had the courage of nothing to lose--not even a pair of breeches--and everything to gain.\n

\"Please,\" said the apparition, \"the pilot\'s gone, and you can\'t put me off!\"\n

The Chief opened his mouth and shut it again. The mouth, and the modification of an eye set for a six-foot trimmer to an eye for a four-foot-ten urchin in a Turkish towel, produced a certain softening. The Red Un, who was like the Chief in that he earned his way by pitting his wits against relentless Nature, smiled a little--a surface smile, with fear just behind.\n

\"The Captain\'s boy\'s my size; I could wear his clothes,\" he suggested.\n

Now, back in that time when the Chief had kept a woman\'s picture in his breast pocket instead of in a drawer of his desk, there had been small furtive hopes, the pride of the Scot to perpetuate his line, the desire of a man for a manchild. The Chief had buried all that in the desk drawer with the picture; but he had gone overboard in his best uniform to rescue a wharf-rat, and he had felt a curious sense of comfort when he held the cold little figure in his arms and was hauled on deck, sputtering dirty river water and broad Scotch, as was his way when excited.\n

\"And where ha\' ye been skulking since yesterday?\" he demanded.\n

\"In the bed where I was put till last night. This morning early----\" he hesitated.\n

\"Don\'t lie! Where were ye?\"\n

\"In a passenger\'s room, under a bed. When the passengers came aboard I had to get out.\"\n

\"How did ye get here?\"\n

This met with silence. Quite suddenly the Chief recognised the connivance of the crew, perhaps, or of a kindly stewardess.\n

\"Who told you this was my cabin?\" A smile this time, rather like the Senior Second\'s when the Chief and he had shaken hands.\n

\"A nigger!\" he said. \"A coloured fella in a white suit.\"\n\n



There was not a darky on the boat. The Red Un, whose code was the truth when possible, but any lie to save a friend--and that\'s the code of a gentleman--sat, defiantly hopeful, arranging the towel to cover as much as possible of his small person.\n

\"You\'re lying! Do you know what we do with liars on this ship? We throw them overboard!\"\n

\"Then I\'m thinking,\" responded the Turkish towel, \"that you\'ll be needing another Chief Engineer before long!\"\n

Now, as it happened, the Chief had no boy that trip. The previous one had been adopted after the last trip by a childless couple who had liked the shape of his nose and the way his eyelashes curled on his cheek. The Chief looked at the Red Un; it was perfectly clear that no one would ever adopt him for the shape of his nose, and he apparently lacked lashes entirely. He rose and took a bathrobe from a hook on the door.\n

\"Here,\" he said; \"cover your legs wi\' that, and say a prayer if ye\' know wan. The Captain\'s a verra hard man wi\' stowaways.\"\n

The Captain, however, who was a gentleman and a navigator and had a sense of humour also, was not hard with the Red Un. It being impracticable to take the boy to him, the great man made a special visit to the boy. The Red Un, in the Chief\'s bathrobe, sat on a chair, with his feet about four inches from the floor, and returned the Captain\'s glare with wide blue eyes.\n

\"Is there any reason, young man, why I shouldn\'t order you to the lockup for the balance of this voyage?\" the Captain demanded, extra grim, and trying not to smile.\n

\"Well,\" said the Red Un, wiggling his legs nervously, \"you\'d have to feed me, wouldn\'t you? And I might as well work for my keep.\"\n

This being a fundamental truth on which most economics and all governments are founded, and the Captain having a boy of his own at home, he gave a grudging consent, for the sake of discipline, to the Red Un\'s working for his keep as the Chief\'s boy, and left. Outside the door he paused.\n

\"The little devil\'s starved,\" he said. \"Put some meat on those ribs, Chief, and--be a bit easy with him!\"\n

This last was facetious, the Chief being known to have the heart of a child.\n

So the Red Un went on the payroll of the line, and requisition was made on the storekeeper for the short-tailed coat and the long trousers, and on the barber for a hair-cut. And in some curious way the Red Un and the Chief hit it off. It might have been a matter of red blood or of indomitable spirit.\n

Spirit enough and to spare had the Red Un. On the trip out he had licked the Captain\'s boy and the Purser\'s boy; on the incoming trip he had lashed the Doctor\'s boy to his triumphant mast, and only three days before he had settled a row in the stokehole by putting hot ashes down the back of a drunken trimmer, and changing his attitude from menace with a steel shovel to supplication and prayer.\n

He had no business in the stokehole, but by that time he knew every corner of the ship--called the engines by name and the men by epithets; had named one of the pumps Marguerite, after the Junior Second\'s best girl; and had taken violent partisanship in the eternal rivalry of the liner between the engine room and the bridge.\n\n



\"Aw, gwan!\" he said to the Captain\'s boy. \"Where\'d you and your Old Man be but for us? In a blasted steel tank, floating about on the bloomin\' sea! What\'s a ship without insides?\"\n

The Captain\'s boy, who was fourteen, and kept his bath sponge in a rubber bag, and shaved now and then with the Captain\'s razor, retorted in kind.\n

\"You fellows below think you\'re the whole bally ship!\" he said loftily. \"Insides is all right--we need \'em in our business. But what\'d your steel tank do, with the engines goin\', if she wasn\'t bein\' navigated? Steamin\' in circles, like a tinklin\' merry-go-round!\"\n

It was some seconds after this that the Purser, a well-intentioned but interfering gentleman with a beard, received the kick that put him in dry dock for two days.\n\n


</string>


    <string name="the_game_part_2">The Game Part 2</string>
    <string name="mary_roberts_rinehart">Mary Roberts Rinehart</string>
    <string name="paragraph02">
    II

    They were three days out of New York on the Red Un\'s second round trip when the Second, still playing the game and almost despairing, made a strategic move. The Red Un was laying out the Chief\'s luncheon on his desk- a clean napkin for a cloth; a glass; silver; a plate; and the menu from the first-cabin dining saloon. The menu was propped against a framed verse:\n

    But I ha\' lived and I ha\' worked! All thanks to Thee, Most High.\n

    And as he placed the menu, the Red Un repeated the words from McAndrew\'s hymn. It had rather got him at first; it was a new philosophy of life. To give thanks for life was understandable, even if unnecessary. But thanks for work! There was another framed card above the desk, more within the Red Un\'s ken: \"Cable crossing! Do not anchor here!\"\n

    The card worked well with the first class, resting in the Chief\'s cabin after the arduous labours of seeing the engines.\n

    The Chief was below, flat on his back in a manhole looking for a staccato note that did not belong in his trained and orderly chorus. There was grease in his sandy hair, and the cranks were only a few inches from his nose. By opening the door the Red Un was able to command the cylinder tops, far below, and the fiddley, which is the roof of hell or a steel grating over the cylinders to walk on-depending on whether one is used to it or not. The Chief was naturally not in sight.\n

    This gave the Red Un two minutes\' leeway--two minutes for exploration. A drawer in the desk, always heretofore locked, was unfastened-that is, the bolt had been shot before the drawer was entirely closed. The Red Un was jealous of that drawer. In two voyages he had learned most of the Chief\'s history and, lacking one of his own, had appropriated it to himself. Thus it was not unusual for him to remark casually, as he stood behind the Chief\'s chair at dinner: \"We\'d better send this here postcard to Cousin Willie, at Edinburgh.\"\n

    \"Ou-ay!\" the Chief would agree, and tear off the postcard of the ship that topped each day\'s menu; but, so far, all hints as to this one drawer had been futile; it remained the one barrier to their perfect confidence, the fly in the ointment of the Red Un\'s content.\n

    Now, at last- Below, a drop of grease in the Chief\'s eye set him wiping and cursing; over his head hammered, banged and lunged his great babies; in the stokehole a gaunt and grimy creature, yclept the Junior Second, stewed in his own sweat and yelled for steam.\n

    The Red Un opened the drawed quickly and thrust in a hand. At first he thought it was empty, working as he did by touch, his eye on the door. Then he found a disappointing something-the lid of a cigar-box! Under that was a photograph. Here was luck! Had the Red Un known it, he had found the only two secrets in his Chief\'s open life. But the picture was disappointing-a snapshot of a young woman, rather slim, with the face obscured by a tennis racket, obviously thrust into the picture at the psychological moment. Poor spoil this-a cigar-box lid and a girl without a face! However, marred as it was, it clearly meant something to the Chief. For on its reverse side was another stanza from McAndrew\'s hymn:\n

    Ye know how hard an idol dies, An\' what that meant to me- E\'en tak\' it for a sacrifice Acceptable to Thee.\n

    The Red Un thrust it back into the drawer, with the lid. If she was dead what did it matter? He was a literal youth-so far, his own words had proved sufficient for his thoughts; it is after thirty that a man finds his emotions bigger than his power of expressing them, and turns to those that have the gift. The Chief was over thirty.\n

    It was as he shut the drawer that he realised he was not alone. The alley door was open and in it stood the Senior Second. The Red Un eyed him unpleasantly.\n

    \"Sneaking!\" said the Second.\n

    \"None of your blamed business!\" replied the Red Un.\n

    The Second, who was really an agreeable person, with a sense of humour, smiled. He rather liked the Red Un.\n\n



    \"Do you know, William,\" he observed-William was the Red Un\'s name-\"I\'d be willing to offer two shillings for an itemised account of what\'s in that drawer?\"\n

    \"Fill it with shillings,\" boasted the Red Un, \"and I\'ll not tell you.\"\n

    \"Three?\" said the Second cheerfully.\n

    \"No.\"\n

    \"Four\"\n

    \"Why don\'t you look yourself?\"\n

    \"Just between gentlemen, that isn\'t done, young man. But if you volunteered the information, and I saw fit to make you a present of, say, a pipe, with a box of tobacco-\"\n

    \"What do you want to know for?\"\n

    \"I guess you know.\"\n

    The Red Un knew quite well. The Chief and the two Seconds were still playing their game, and the Chief was still winning; but even the Red Un did not know how the Chief won-and as for the two Seconds and the Third and the Fourth, they were quite stumped.\n

    This was the game: In bad weather, when the ports are closed and first-class passengers are yapping for air, it is the province of the engine room to see that they get it. An auxiliary engine pumps cubic feet of atmosphere into every cabin through a series of airtrunks.\n

    So far so good. But auxiliaries take steam; and it is exceedingly galling to a Junior or Senior, wagering more than he can afford on the run in his watch, to have to turn valuable steam to auxiliaries-\"So that a lot of blooming nuts may smoke in their bunks!\" as the Third put it.\n

    The first move in the game is the Chief\'s, who goes to bed and presumably to sleep. After that it\'s the engine-room move, which gives the first class time to settle down and then shuts off the airpumps. Now there is no noise about shutting off the air in the trunks. It flows or it does not flow. The game is to see whether the Chief wakens when the air stops or does not. So far he had always wakened.\n

    It was uncanny. It was worse than that-it was damnable! Did not the Old Man sleep at all?-not that he was old, but every Chief is the Old Man behind his back. Everything being serene, and the engine-room clock marking twelve-thirty, one of the Seconds would shut off the air very gradually; the auxiliary would slow down, wheeze, pant and die-and within two seconds the Chief\'s bell would ring and an angry voice over the telephone demand what the several kinds of perdition had happened to the air! Another trick in the game to the Chief!\n

    It had gone past joking now: had moved up from the uncanny to the impossible, from the impossible to the enraging. Surreptitious search of the Chief\'s room had shown nothing but the one locked drawer. They had taken advantage of the Chief\'s being laid up in Antwerp with a boil on his neck to sound the cabin for hidden wires. They had asked the ship\'s doctor anxiously how long a man could do without sleep. The doctor had quoted Napoleon.\n


    \"If at any time,\" observed the Second pleasantly, \"you would like that cigarette case the barber is selling, you know how to get it.\"\n

    \"Thanks, old man,\" said the Red Un loftily, with his eye on the wall.\n

    The Second took a step forward and thought better of it.\n

    \"Better think about it!\"\n

    \"I was thinking of something else,\" said the Red Un, still staring at the wall. The Second followed his eye. The Red Un was gazing intently at the sign which said: \"Cable crossing! Do not anchor here!\"\n

    As the Second slammed out, the Chief crawled from his manhole and struggled out of his greasy overalls. Except for his face, he was quite tidy. He ran an eye down the port tunnel, where the shaft revolved so swiftly that it seemed to be standing still, to where at the after end came the racing of the screw as it lifted, bearded with scud, out of the water.\n

    \"It looks like weather to-night,\" he observed, with a twinkle, to the Fourth. \"There\'ll aye be air wanted.\" But the Fourth was gazing at a steam gauge.\n\n
</string>

</resources>